这是乐山市二零二一年初中学业水平考试英语科听力部分。该部分分为两节。注意回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听每段材料前，你将有五秒钟的时间阅读每小题。听完后，每小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。听力内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到客观题答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
When did you join NASA?
Six years ago.
And how many times have you flown in a spacecraft?
Three times. How did you feel when you were in the spacecraft?
I enjoyed it.
It was very exciting.
Have you worked on the space station?
Yes, I have.
I've already been twice.
Have you seen the Earth from the space station?
Yes, I have.
It was very beautiful, very blue.
How wonderful! What did you feel when you saw it?
I wanted to cry.
I thought about my family.
Did you think about your family a when you were on the space station?
All the time.
I'm sure. Tell me, why did you decide to be an astronaut?
I've always been interested in space.
It's so exciting.
Do you think there's life on other planets?
Yes, I do.
The universe is so big.
There are so many galaxies, so many solar systems.
But we haven't found anything yet.
We've only just begun to look.
Give us time.
Another hundred years, perhaps?
Well, thank you for this interview.
It's been great to talk to you.
Thank you. of part.
事因到此结束。听力考试正式开始，请看听力部分第一节。第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的。
A, B, and Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话前，你将有五秒钟的时间阅读有关小题。听完后，每小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话读两遍。例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。
Yes, it's 9.15 pounds.
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
你将有五秒。秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择项，并在试卷上将其标出。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的。有关内容。
Would you like to go for walk or have a swim this Saturday?
I'm not sure.
Well, why don't we go boating?
That'll be more relaxing.
You're right. Would you like to for a walk or have a swim this Saturday?
I'm not sure.
Well, why don't we go boating?
That'll be more relaxing.
You're right. Why did it take you so much time to come here?
We are almost late for the film.
My car was broken and there's no bus stop near my house, so I walked here.
Why did it take you so much time to come here?
We are almost late for the film.
My car was broken and there's no bus stop near my house, so I walked here.
Oh, what a terrible day!
We've had three raining days.
I want to know when it is going to be fine.
The weatherman says it's going to be a sunny day tomorrow.
Oh, what a terrible day!
We've had three raining days.
I want to know when it is going to be fine.
The weatherman says it's going to be a sunny day tomorrow.
Congratulations! I hear you are going to join the army.
Thanks, but actually, it's my brother who is going to join the army.
I'm going to university.
I wish to become a doctor in the future.
Congratulations! I hear you are going to join the army.
Thanks, but actually, it's my brother who is going to join the army.
I'm going to university.
I wish to become a doctor in the future.
What happened to you?
Were you in a car accident?
No, I broke my leg when climbing the mountain during my vacation.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I spent the holiday swimming, sailing and playing tennis.
What happened to you?
Were you in a car accident?
No, I broke my leg when climbing the mountain during my vacation.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I spent the holiday swimming, sailing and playing tennis.
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面五段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后。哦，有几个小题。从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间，每段对话或独白读两遍。听第六段材料，回答第六。七题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
What's the best gift you have ever received?
A mobile phone.
When did you get it?
I got it on my 16th birthday.
Who gave it to you?
My uncle. What a lucky boy!
May I have a look?
Oh, sorry. My math teacher has taken it away because I used it in class.
What a pity!
You should say sorry to and promise you will never bring it to school.
I think she will not be angry with you.
I will. What's the best gift you have ever received?
A mobile phone.
When did you get it?
I got it on my 16th birthday.
Who gave it to you?
My uncle. What a lucky boy!
May I have a look?
Oh, sorry. My math teacher has taken it away because I used it in class.
What a pity!
You should say sorry to her and promise you will never bring it to school.
I think she will not be angry with you.
I will. questions.
听第七段材料，回答第八至十题。现在你。有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题
Good morning! Can I help you?
Yes, I'd like to have a room for two nights.
Well, we still have rooms on the third, the fourth, and the seventh floor.
Okay, I'd like to live on the third floor.
How much should I pay for one night?
$80. Do you have hot water in the room?
Yes, 24 hours.
Can anyone show me to my room?
Look, that boy over there will.
Thanks. Good morning!
Can I help you?
Yes, I'd like to have a room for two nights.
Well, we still have rooms on the third, the fourth, and the seventh floor.
Okay, I'd like to live on the third floor.
How much should I pay for one night?
$80. Do you have hot water in the room?
Yes, 24 hours.
Can anyone show me to my room?
Look, that boy over there will.
I'd much for room?
听第八段材料，回答第十一至十三题。现在你有十五秒。中的时间阅读这三个小题
hours. I'd like room How much one
$80. have Yes, Hi Joy, would you like to save the environment?
I don't know.
What can I do?
Well, first, you can start by turning off the lights.
Yes, that's easy.
Sometimes I turn on the lights without thinking.
What's next? Second, you can ride a bike.
Don't take a bus or a taxi if you don't have to.
That will save money too.
What else? Try to recycle paper.
Hmm, newspapers, magazines, mail.
We get a lot of paper at home.
Good idea. last, take a bag when you go shopping.
Don't use plastic bags.
Okay, my parents do most of the shopping.
I'll tell them.
Hi Joy, would you like to save the environment?
I don't know.
What can I do?
Well, first, you can start by turning off the lights.
Yes, that's easy.
Sometimes I turn on the lights without thinking.
What's next? Second, you can ride a bike.
Don't take a bus or a taxi if you don't have to.
That will save money too.
What else? Try to recycle paper.
Hmm, newspapers, magazines, mail.
We get a lot of paper at home.
Good idea. And last, take a bag when you go shopping.
Don't use plastic bags.
Okay, my parents do most of the shopping.
I'll tell them.
听第九段材料，回答第十四至十六题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。咦。
Okay, my parents most shopping.
parents don't don't don't to.
嗨，
Okay, my parents Okay,
my parents parents don't don't to.
Okay, my parents my parents do Would you like to go to watch the movie Hi Mom with
me? It is very popular.
Are you interested?
Of course I am.
Thanks for inviting me.
What time shall we go?
The movie starts at 11 am.
We'd better get there at least half an hour earlier.
I think I could pick you up at your house at 10 am.
Is that okay with you?
Yeah, great. Okay, I will see you tomorrow morning, Lucy.
Okay, Jack. See you then.
听第十段材料，回答第十七至二十题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Welcome to Volunteer Club.
I'm Susan. Now I'd like to tell you something about the activity this Saturday.
We are going to plant trees in Central Park.
You are going to be divided into seven small groups.
We will take the school bus to the park.
We will meet at our school gate at 6.30 in the morning.
It will take us about one and a half hours to get there, and we will come back to
school at 6 o in the afternoon.
Here are some suggestions for you.
First, you'd better wear comfortable shoes, because we will be working in the park
for nearly eight hours.
Second, you'd better bring your umbrella.
If it rains, you will need it.
Third, bring your own lunch with you.
The school only provides bottles of water.
In my opinion, this activity is very useful.
It can help us young people learn some working skills.
You will also make more friends through this activity.
What's more, you will learn how to enjoy nature.
I hope all of you will have a good time this Saturday.
Welcome to Volunteer Club.
I'm Susan. Now, I'd like to tell you something about the activity this Saturday.
We are going to plant trees in Central Park.
You are going to be divided into seven small groups.
We will take the school bus to the park.
We will meet at our school gate at 6.30 in the morning.
It will take us about one and a half hours to get there.
And we will come back to school at 6 o in the afternoon.
Here are some suggestions for you.
First, you'd better wear comfortable shoes, because we will be working in the park
for nearly eight hours.
Second, you'd better bring your umbrella.
If it rains, you will need it.
Third, bring your own lunch with you.
The school only provides bottles of water.
In my opinion, this activity is very useful.
It can help us young people learn some working skills.
You will also make more friends through this activity.
What's more, you will learn how to enjoy nature.
I hope all of you will have a good time this Saturday.
This is Thank you.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂。到客观题答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
you. you. you.
Thank This is of
听力部分到此结束。